DESPOINA TOUSKA

Thessaloniki, Greece

d3py.tousk@gmail.com \leq Linkedin \leq ORCID \leq Google Scolar

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Software engineer with 2+ years of experience as a research associate in the machine learning and computer vision fields. Posses abilities to identify, understand and translate program requirements into sustainable, advanced technical solutions through Python, C, C++, JavaScript, and other programs for continuous improvement of AI technologies.

EDUCATION

Aristotle University of Thessaloniki

Thessaloniki, Greece

MSc in Electrical and Computer Engineering

October 2013 - April 2020

- Cumulative GPA: 8.35/10
- Relevant Coursework: Pattern Recognition, Parallel & Distributed Systems, Probabilities & Statistics, Data Structures, Structured Programming, Robotics, Database Systems

Centre for Research and Technology Hellas (CERTH)

Thessaloniki, Greece March 2018 - May 2018

Thessaloniki, Greece

Collaboration for thesis completion

• Thesis: Video Forgery Detection using Autoencoder and Recurrent Neural Networks (link)

• Grade: 10/10

EXPERIENCE

Centre for Research and Technology Hellas (CERTH)

Machine Learning Engineer and Research Associate

Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto (ISEP)

Software Engineer and Research Intern

Porto, Portugal October 2019 - February, 2020

September 2020 - Present

Centre for Research and Technology Hellas (CERTH)

Software Engineer and Research Intern

Thessaloniki, Greece November 2018 - September 2019

PUBLICATIONS

- D. Touska, K. Gkountakos, K. Ioannidis, T. Tsikrika, S. Vrochidis, I. Kompatsiaris. Graph-Based Data Association in Multiple Object Tracking: A Survey. MMM2023. 2023. (accepted for publication)
- Gkountakos, K., Touska, D., Ioannidis, K., Tsikrika, T., Vrochidis, S., & Kompatsiaris, I. Spatio-temporal activity detection and recognition in untrimmed surveillance videos. ICMR. 2021.
- Gkountakos, K., Galanopoulos, D., Touska, D., Ioannidis, K., Vrochidis, S., Mezaris, V., & Kompatsiaris, I. ITI-CERTH participation in ActEV and AVS Tracks of TRECVID 2021. TRECVID. 2021.
- Gkountakos, K., Galanopoulos, D., Mpakratsas, M., Touska, D., Moumtzidou, A., Ioannidis, K., ... & Kompatsiaris, I. (2020). ITI-CERTH participation in TRECVID 2020. TRECVID. 2020.
- Zampoglou, M., Markatopoulou, F., Mercier, G., Touska, D., Apostolidis, E., Papadopoulos, S., ... & Kompatsiaris, I. Detecting tampered videos with multimedia forensics and deep learning. MMM2019, 2019

SKILLS

Languages: English (fluent, C2, IELTS: 7.5/9), Greek (native), German (beginner, A2).

Programming Languages: Python (advanced), C/C++ (intermediate), JavaScript (intermediate), HTML (intermediate), CSS (intermediate), SQL (beginner).

Libraries: PyTorch, Keras, Tensorflow, TensorFlow.js, NumPy, Pandas, Sci-Kit Learn.

Production Tools: Docker, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Git